<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Nnamdi&#039;s Notes</title>
      <link>https://whoisnnamdi.com/notes</link>
      <description>Last 10 notes on Nnamdi&#039;s Notes</description>
      <generator>Quartz -- quartz.jzhao.xyz</generator>
      <item>
    <title>The Adaptive Lasso and Its Oracle Properties</title>
    <link>https://whoisnnamdi.com/notes/@zouAdaptiveLassoIts2006</link>
    <guid>https://whoisnnamdi.com/notes/@zouAdaptiveLassoIts2006</guid>
    <description>The Adaptive Lasso and Its Oracle Properties Hui Zou Abstract The lasso is a popular technique for simultaneous estimation and variable selection. Lasso variable selection has been shown to be consistent under certain conditions.</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 23:35:04 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Recursive Language Models</title>
    <link>https://whoisnnamdi.com/notes/@zhangRecursiveLanguageModels</link>
    <guid>https://whoisnnamdi.com/notes/@zhangRecursiveLanguageModels</guid>
    <description>Recursive Language Models Alex L. Zhang, Tim Kraska, Omar Khattab Their implementation: github.com/alexzhang13/rlm References paperreadonline.</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 23:35:04 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>1000 Layer Networks for Self-Supervised RL: Scaling Depth Can Enable New Goal-Reaching Capabilities</title>
    <link>https://whoisnnamdi.com/notes/@wang1000LayerNetworks2025</link>
    <guid>https://whoisnnamdi.com/notes/@wang1000LayerNetworks2025</guid>
    <description>1000 Layer Networks for Self-Supervised RL: Scaling Depth Can Enable New Goal-Reaching Capabilities Kevin Wang, Ishaan Javali, Michał Bortkiewicz, Tomasz Trzciński, Benjamin ...</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 23:35:04 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Dynamic covariate balancing: Estimating treatment effects over time with potential local projections</title>
    <link>https://whoisnnamdi.com/notes/@vivianoDynamicCovariateBalancing2023</link>
    <guid>https://whoisnnamdi.com/notes/@vivianoDynamicCovariateBalancing2023</guid>
    <description>Dynamic covariate balancing: Estimating treatment effects over time with potential local projections Davide Viviano, Jelena Bradic – 2023 Main difference from standard local ...</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 23:35:04 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Systematic shifts in scaling behavior based on organizational strategy in universities</title>
    <link>https://whoisnnamdi.com/notes/@taylorSystematicShiftsScaling2021</link>
    <guid>https://whoisnnamdi.com/notes/@taylorSystematicShiftsScaling2021</guid>
    <description>Systematic shifts in scaling behavior based on organizational strategy in universities Ryan C. Taylor, Xiaofan Liang, Manfred D. Laubichler, Geoffrey B.</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 23:35:04 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Dynamic Factor Models, Factor-Augmented Vector Autoregressions, and Structural Vector Autoregressions in Macroeconomics</title>
    <link>https://whoisnnamdi.com/notes/@stockDynamicFactorModels2016</link>
    <guid>https://whoisnnamdi.com/notes/@stockDynamicFactorModels2016</guid>
    <description>Dynamic Factor Models, Factor-Augmented Vector Autoregressions, and Structural Vector Autoregressions in Macroeconomics J.H. Stock, M.W. Watson Link Abstract This chapter provides an overview of and user’s guide to dynamic factor models (DFMs), their estimation, and their uses in empirical macroeconomics.</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 23:35:04 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Identification and Estimation of Dynamic Causal Effects in Macroeconomics Using External Instruments</title>
    <link>https://whoisnnamdi.com/notes/@stockIdentificationEstimationDynamic2018</link>
    <guid>https://whoisnnamdi.com/notes/@stockIdentificationEstimationDynamic2018</guid>
    <description>Identification and Estimation of Dynamic Causal Effects in Macroeconomics Using External Instruments James H. Stock, Mark W. Watson Link Video Abstract External sources of as-if randomness — that is, external instruments — can be used to identify the dynamic causal effects of macroeconomic shocks.</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 23:35:04 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Scaling LLM Test-Time Compute Optimally can be More Effective than Scaling Model Parameters</title>
    <link>https://whoisnnamdi.com/notes/@snellScalingLLMTestTime2024</link>
    <guid>https://whoisnnamdi.com/notes/@snellScalingLLMTestTime2024</guid>
    <description>Scaling LLM Test-Time Compute Optimally can be More Effective than Scaling Model Parameters Charlie Snell, Jaehoon Lee, Kelvin Xu, Aviral Kumar – 2024 Scaling test-time compute ...</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 23:35:04 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Essays in Macroeconometrics</title>
    <link>https://whoisnnamdi.com/notes/@plagborg-mollerEssaysMacroeconometrics</link>
    <guid>https://whoisnnamdi.com/notes/@plagborg-mollerEssaysMacroeconometrics</guid>
    <description>Essays in Macroeconometrics Mikkel Plagborg-Møller Link Abstract This dissertation consists of three independent chapters on econometric methods for macroeconomic analysis ...</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 23:35:04 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Boosting: Why You Can Use the Hp Filter</title>
    <link>https://whoisnnamdi.com/notes/@phillipsBoostingWhyYou2021</link>
    <guid>https://whoisnnamdi.com/notes/@phillipsBoostingWhyYou2021</guid>
    <description>Boosting: Why You Can Use the Hp Filter Peter C. B. Phillips, Zhentao Shi Abstract We propose a procedure of iterating the HP filter to produce a smarter smoothing device, called the boosted HP (bHP) filter, based on L2-boosting in machine learning.</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 23:35:04 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>